A Guide to the School of Education/VSU- Record Group 1927-
Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
Special Collections and Archives, Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
A Guide to the School of Education/Record Group 1927-1961
Special Collections and Archives, Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
1927-1961
Records of the oldest school for teachers education in the state of virginia. Correspondence, minutes all documenting all of the early years in the school of education.
This archival document was transfered to archives.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Biographical/Historical Information
The Virginia Normal and Collegiate was charted on march 6, 1882. With the following mandate to provide equality for the higher education of the colored youth and to furnish competent teachers for the colored schools of the state. with this charter the first state supported school in Virginia for teachers was established.
During the first twenty-three years, 1883-1906, the Normal Department offered a single three-year curriculum consisting partly of elementary and high school subjects including music, drawing, sloyd, sewing, cooking, physical "culture" and partlyof education courses: the science and art of teaching, moral philosophy, psychology and "general reviews".
The movement toward specialization began in 1909, when students were permitted to select teaching, domestic science or art, agriculture, mechanical drawing, or buisness. Graduation from high school was first required for entrance to teacher-training courses in 1915.
When the four-year college curriculum was reinstated by the state in 1923, The bachelor of science degree in education was the first to be accredited as a "Class a teachers college. In 1925, the college was offered its first differentiated curricula for the seperate training of high school and supervisors, and teachers of public school music.
A major in physical education followed in 1926; the department of secondary education emerged in 1930 offering a curriculum for secondary school principals and teachers; and the department of art was offered in 1933.
With the introduction of liberal arts in 1930, the department of education became the Division of Education, a separate administrative unit of the College offering the four curricula organized by the departments of elementary education, secondary education,
music and physical education. With the introduction of liberal arts in 1930, the department of education became the Division of Education, a separate administrative unit of the College.
The division of education became The School of Education in the 1960's. In 1995 The School of Education was emerged with The School of Humanities and Social Science therefore becoming the School of Liberal Arts and Education.
Scope and Content Information
These records reflect the administration of Edna Meade Colson Phd. Of the school of education during her tenure. During this time the school of education was involved in almost every aspect of the University and the community.
Contained in this record group are routine administrative manners common in all schools within a university setting. the materials reflect the philosophy and the role that education can take in solving societies problems. The records reflect the difficulties faced by an HBCU during the time of "Jim Crowism."
Arrangement
Its a Record Group
Contents List
- Administrative Research
  - Annual Reports
    - Annual Reports 1938-1939 (Box-folder 1:1)
    - Annual Reports Educational Extension Department 1937 (Box-folder 1:2)
    - Annual Reports, Extension Department 1938 (Box-folder 1:3)
    - Annual Reports, Blanford School 1950-1951 (Box-folder 1:4)
    - Annual Report 1946 (Box-folder 2:1)
    - Annual Report 1947-1948 (Box-folder 2:2)
    - Annual Report 1949-1950 (Box-folder 2:3)
    - Annual Report 1950-1951 (Box-folder 2:4)
    - Annual Report 1951-1952 (Box-folder 2:5)
    - Annual Report 1952-1953 (Box-folder 2:6)
    - Annual Report Secondary Education 1952 (Box-folder 3:1)
    - Annual Report Secondary Education 1953 (Box-folder 3:2)
    - Annual Report Secondary Education 1954 (Box-folder 3:3)
    - Annual Report Secondary Education 1955 (Box-folder 3:4)
    - Annual Report Secondary Education 1956 (Box-folder 3:5)
    - Annual Report Secondary Education 1957 (Box-folder 3:6)
    - Annual Report Secondary Education 1958 (Box-folder 3:7)
    - Annual Report Secondary Education 1959 (Box-folder 3:8)
    - Annual Report Secondary Education 1960 (Box-folder 3:9)
    - Annual Report Secondary Education 1961 (Box-folder 3:10)
    - Annual Report Secondary Education 1962 (Box-folder 3:11)
    - Annual Report Secondary Education 1963 (Box-folder 3:12)
    - Annual Report Secondary Education 1964 (Box-folder 3:13)
    - Annual Report Secondary Education 1965 (Box-folder 3:14)
    - Annual Report Secondary Education 1966 (Box-folder 3:15)
    - Annual Report Secondary Education 1949 (Box-folder 3:16)
  - Test
    - Test Results administered to New Students 1942 (Box-folder 4:1)
    - Test Results administered to New Students 1943 (Box-folder 4:2)
    - Test Results administered to New Students 1944 (Box-folder 4:3)
    - Test Results administered to New Students 1945 (Box-folder 4:4)
    - Test Results administered to New Students 1946 (Box-folder 4:5)
    - Test Results administered to New Students 1947-1948 (Box-folder 4:6)
    - Test Results administered to New Students 1948 (Box-folder 4:7)
    - Test Results administered to New Students 1948 (Box-folder 4:8)
    - Test Results administered to New Students 1949 (Box-folder 4:9)
    - Test Results administered to New Students 1950-1951 (Box-folder 4:10)
    - Test Results administered to New Students 1951-1952 (Box-folder 4:11)
    - Test Results administered to New Students 1952-1953 (Box-folder 4:12)
    - Test Results administered to New Students 1954-1955 (Box-folder 4:13)
    - Test results administered to New Students 1955-1956 (Box-folder 5:1)
    - Test results administered to New Students 1956-1957 (Box-folder 5:2)
    - Test results administered to New Students 1957-1958 (Box-folder 5:3)
    - Test results administered to New Students 1959-1960 (Box-folder 5:4)
    - Test results administered to New Students 1960-1961 (Box-folder 5:5)
    - Test results administered to New Students 1960-1961 (Box-folder 5:6)
    - Test results administered to New Students 1961-1962 (Box-folder 5:7)
  - Department manuals and guide lines
    - A manual for directed teachings at D. Webster Davis High School n.d. (Box-folder 6:1)
    - A Description of the Teacher Education program. The NCATE 1963 (Box-folder 6:2)
    - Guidelines for Cooperating Teachers The Professional Laboratory Experiences Committee 1965 (Box-folder 6:3)
    - Toward More Effective supervision of Student Teaching 1963 (Box-folder 6:4)
- Correspondence
  - By subject heading
    - The AAUM-Correspondence 1959-1961 (Box-folder 7:1)
    - The AAUM-Correspondence 1962-1965 (Box-folder 7:2)
    - Adult Education (minutes) n.d. (Box-folder 7:3)
    - Adult Education 1938, 1945 (Box-folder 7:4)
    - Adult Education 1946-1948 (Box-folder 7:5)
    - Adult Education 1947, 1949 (Box-folder 7:6)
    - Air Raid Committee n.d. (Box-folder 7:7)
    - American Education Week 1936 (Box-folder 7:8)
    - American Education Week 1944-1951 (Box-folder 7:9)
    - American Education Radio Script 1948 (Box-folder 7:10)
    - American Education Week 1951 (Box-folder 7:11)
    - American Education Week 1952 (Box-folder 7:12)
    - The American Red Cross 1946-1947 (Box-folder 7:13)
    - Art Department 1948 (Box-folder 8:1)
    - Art Department Correspondence 1949 (Box-folder 8:2)
    - Art Department Correspondence 1950 (Box-folder 8:3)
    - Art Department 1951 (Box-folder 8:4)
    - Art Department 1952 (Box-folder 8:5)
    - Art Department Correspondence 1953 (Box-folder 8:6)
    - Art Department Correspondence 1955 (Box-folder 8:7)
    - Art Department workshops 1948-1949 (Box-folder 8:8)
    - Art Department List of Holdings n.d. (Box-folder 8:9)
    - Art Department 1938, 1953 (Box-folder 8:10)
    - Art Department printed programs 1950 (Box-folder 8:11)
    - Art Department list of Art Instructers in Virginia n.d. (Box-folder 8:12)
    - Art Department 1951 (Box-folder 8:13)
    - Art Department Newsclippings n.d. (Box-folder 8:14)
    - Art Department 1952 (Box-folder 8:15)
    - Audio Visual Correspondence 1947-1952 (Box-folder 8:16)
    - Audio Visual Monthly- reports 1949-1950 (Box-folder 8:17)
    - Audio Visual Monthly 1947 (Box-folder 8:18)
    - Audio Visual- printed n.d. (Box-folder 8:19)
    - Blandford Training 1937 (Box-folder 9:1)
    - Blandford School 1950-1953 (Box-folder 9:2)
    - Critic Report- Blanford School 1937 (Box-folder 9:3)
    - Books 1938-1946 (Box-folder 9:4)
    - Pamplets (Books) n.d. (Box-folder 9:5)
    - Buck, J.L. Blair 1947-1948 (Box-folder 9:6)
    - Buck, J.L. Blair 1949-1958 (Box-folder 9:7)
    - Buck, J.L. Blair 1948-1951 (Box-folder 9:8)
    - Buck, J.L. Blair 1952 (Box-folder 9:9)
    - Chesterfield County 1946 (Box-folder 9:10)
    - Christianburg Workshop 1944 (Box-folder 9:11)
    - Civics 1933, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 9:12)
    - College Correspondence 1934,1953 (Box-folder 9:13)
    - College Counseling Services 1932-1946 (Box-folder 9:14)
    - College Counseling Services 1952-1953 (Box-folder 9:15)
    - College Counseling Services 1949-1950 (Box-folder 9:16)
    - Colson, Cortland M. 1943-1949 (Box-folder 9:17)
    - Colson, Cortland M. 1950-1951 (Box-folder 9:18)
    - Edna M. Colson 1937,41,43,46, 51-53 (Box-folder 10:1)
    - Commission, Higher Education for Negroes 1934-1938 (Box-folder 10:2)
    - Committee on General Education 1948 (Box-folder 10:3)
    - Comp. Programs of Education Va Schools 1946 (Box-folder 10:4)
    - Conferences n.d. (Box-folder 10:5)
    - Conference Papers n.d. (Box-folder 10:6)
    - Conference-One Teacher Schools n.d. (Box-folder 10:7)
    - Conference one Teacher Rural School Atlanta University 1933 (Box-folder 10:8)
    - Conference-Negro Education 1938 (Box-folder 10:9)
    - Study Conference (White) 1947 (Box-folder 10:10)
    - Study Conference (Black) 1947 (Box-folder 10:11)
    - Conference Report 1954 (Box-folder 10:12)
    - General Correspondence 1925-1931 (Box-folder 10:13)
    - General Correspondence 1928-1929 (Box-folder 10:14)
    - General Correspondence 1935 (Box-folder 10:15)
    - General Correspondence 1968 (Box-folder 10:16)
    - General Correspondence-Directories of Teachers 1943-1944 (Box-folder 10:17)
    - General Correspondence-Directories of Teachers 1945 (Box-folder 10:18)
    - General Correspondence- Federation Women's Club July 1948 (Box-folder 11:1)
    - Correspondence-Cure 1931-1950 (Box-folder 11:2)
    - Correspondence-dean Director of Industrial Education 1928-1929 (Box-folder 11:3)
    - Correspondence-Dean Office of Registar 1927-1929 (Box-folder 11:4)
    - Correspondence-Dean President 1927-1929 (Box-folder 11:5)
    - Counseling 1937-1943 (Box-folder 11:6)
    - Curriculum 1946 (Box-folder 11:7)
    - Curriculum 1949-1953 (Box-folder 11:8)
    - Curriculum Materials 1931-1934 (Box-folder 11:9)
    - Curriculum Material Correspondence 1934-1940 (Box-folder 11:10)
    - Curriculum 1933 (Box-folder 11:11)
    - Curriculum Revisions August 18, 1933-1935 (Box-folder 11:12)
    - Curriculum-State Committee 1940 (Box-folder 11:13)
    - Daniel, r. P. (President) 1949-1950 (Box-folder 11:14)
    - Daniel, R.P. (President) 1951 (Box-folder 11:15)
    - Daniel, R.P. (President) 1952-1953 (Box-folder 11:16)
    - Daniel- The Old Dominion Medical Society 1956 (Box-folder 12:1)
    - Daniels- Academic Cabinet n.d. (Box-folder 12:2)
    - Dean of the College 1939-1948 (Box-folder 12:3)
    - Dean of the College 1949-1953 (Box-folder 12:4)
    - Dean Johnston 1922-1933 (Box-folder 12:5)
    - Directors Meeting 1936-1941 (Box-folder 12:6)
    - Directors Meeting 1942-1943 (Box-folder 12:7)
    - Directed Teachings 1930-1935 (Box-folder 12:8)
    - Directed Teachings 1936-1939 (Box-folder 12:9)
    - Directed Teachings 1940-1945 (Box-folder 12:10)
    - Division of Education 1944 (Box-folder 12:11)
    - Division of Education 1944 (Box-folder 12:12)
    - Division of Education July-August 1944 (Box-folder 12:13)
    - Division of Education 1951 (Box-folder 12:14)
    - Division of Education Correspondence 1927-1949 (Box-folder 12:15)
    - Division of Education Correspondence 1950-1951 (Box-folder 12:16)
    - Division Report 1939 (Box-folder 12:17)
    - Division of Education (Faculty Minutes) 1946-1947 (Box-folder 13:1)
    - Division of Education (Faculty Minutes) 1948 (Box-folder 13:2)
    - Division of Education Meetings 1948 (Box-folder 13:3)
    - Division of Education Meetings 1948-1949 (Box-folder 13:4)
    - Division of Education Meetings 1950-1953 (Box-folder 13:5)
    - Division of Education October- December 1948 (Box-folder 13:6)
    - Education 1929-1935 (Box-folder 13:7)
    - Education 1929-1935 (Box-folder 13:8)
    - Basic Education 13:9 (Box-folder 13:9)
    - Education Council 1951 (Box-folder 13:10)
    - General Education Papers n.d. (Box-folder 13:11)
    - General Education Papers 1944-1947 (Box-folder 13:12)
    - General Education Papers 1948-1949 (Box-folder 13:13)
    - Education Issues 1939 (Box-folder 13:14)
    - Educational Policies 1939-1940 (Box-folder 13:15)
    - Educational Policies 1941, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 13:16)
    - Educational Policies n.d. (Box-folder 13:17)
    - Educational Problems n.d. (Box-folder 14:1)
    - elementary School 1946-1947 (Box-folder 14:2)
    - Elementary Education Department 1947-1953 (Box-folder 14:3)
    - Elementary Education Department 1953 (Box-folder 14:4)
    - Improving Elementary Education 1940 (Box-folder 14:5)
    - Elementary School 1941 (Box-folder 14:6)
    - Elementary School 1944-1947 (Box-folder 14:7)
    - Elementary Education- Secondary School Study 1938-1951 (Box-folder 14:8)
    - Ethics March 1944 (Box-folder 14:9)
    - Executive Council 1933-1937 (Box-folder 14:10)
    - Executive Council 1938-1943 (Box-folder 14:11)
    - Executive Council 1944-1952 (Box-folder 14:12)
    - Executive Council 1952-1953 (Box-folder 14:13)
    - Executive Council n.d. (Box-folder 14:14)
    - Extension Department 1932 (Box-folder 15:1)
    - Extension 1933-1936 (Box-folder 15:2)
    - Extension 1937-1947 (Box-folder 15:3)
    - Extension Department 1936-1944 (Box-folder 15:4)
    - Extension Department 1945-1947 (Box-folder 15:5)
    - Extension Department 1944-1952 (Box-folder 15:6)
    - Extension Department n.d. (Box-folder 15:7)
    - Faculty Correspondence 1947 (Box-folder 15:8)
    - Faculty Correspondence 1948-1949 (Box-folder 15:9)
    - Faculty Correspondence 1948-1950 (Box-folder 15:10)
    - Faculty Correspondence 1950 (Box-folder 16:1)
    - Faculty Correspondence 1951 (Box-folder 16:2)
    - Faculty Study Club n.d. (Box-folder 16:3)
    - Faculty Study Club 1941 (Box-folder 16:4)
    - Faculty Study Club Problems to Study n.d. (Box-folder 16:5)
    - Faculty Study Club Minutes and Reports 1942 (Box-folder 16:6)
    - Faculty Study Club Correspondence 1929, 1931-1933 (Box-folder 16:7)
    - Faculty Study Club Correspondence 1932, 1943 (Box-folder 16:8)
    - Faculty Study Club Reports 1930, 1932-1934 (Box-folder 16:9)
    - Faculty Study Club Programs 1931-1932 (Box-folder 16:10)
    - Faculty Division of Education n.d. (Box-folder 16:11)
    - Federal Relief 1933 (Box-folder 16:12)
    - Federal Projects Correspondence 1933-1941 (Box-folder 16:13)
    - Federal Projects Problems of Negro Education 1934-1941 (Box-folder 16:14)
    - Federal Projects Problems of Negro Education n.d. (Box-folder 16:15)
    - Form Letters n.d. (Box-folder 16:16)
    - Foster, L.H. (President) 1941-1942 (Box-folder 16:17)
    - Luther H. Foster Correspondence 1943 (Box-folder 16:18)
    - Luther H. Foster Correspondence 1944 (Box-folder 17:1)
    - Luther H. Foster Correspondence 1945 (Box-folder 17:2)
    - Luther H. Foster Correspondence 1945 (Box-folder 17:3)
    - Luther H. Foster Correspondence 1948 (Box-folder 17:4)
    - Luther H. Foster Correspondence 1949 (Box-folder 17:5)
    - Luther H. Foster Correspondence 1949 (Box-folder 17:6)
    - 4th Annual Institute 1954 (Box-folder 17:7)
    - Fundamental Program in Education Conference 1940 (Box-folder 17:8)
    - Future Teachers of America 1945-1952 (Box-folder 17:9)
    - Future Teachers of America 1953 (Box-folder 17:10)
    - Gandy, John M. 1937-1946 (Box-folder 17:11)
    - Graduates School Minutes & Reports 1935-1936 (Box-folder 17:12)
    - Graduate Commitee 1939-1947 (Box-folder 17:13)
    - Graduat Studies Division Correspondence 1945-1952 (Box-folder 17:14)
    - Graduate Offerings 1938-1939 (Box-folder 17:15)
    - Guidance Materials n.d. (Box-folder 17:16)
    - Guidance Minutes n.d. (Box-folder 17:17)
    - Guidance Test Results n.d. (Box-folder 17:18)
    - Guidance New Student Information 1931-1932 (Box-folder 18:1)
    - Guidance Printed n.d. (Box-folder 18:2)
    - Guidance Correspondence 1930, 1949 (Box-folder 18:3)
    - Guidance Bulletins 1930-1931 (Box-folder 18:4)
    - Guidance Reports 1933-1936 (Box-folder 18:5)
    - Guidance Facts Concerning Freshman 1936 (Box-folder 18:6)
    - Guidance Orientation Courses 1932 (Box-folder 18:7)
    - Guidance Activities n.d. (Box-folder 18:8)
    - Guidance Working Papers n.d. (Box-folder 18:9)
    - Miss Hamlin 1933-1945 (Box-folder 18:10)
    - Hamlin, Wilhelmina E. (Miss) n.d. (Box-folder 18:11)
    - Harris, Viola B. (Mrs.) n.d. (Box-folder 18:12)
    - High School Bulletin n.d. (Box-folder 18:13)
    - High School Correspondence 1937-1939 (Box-folder 18:14)
    - High School Correspondence 1940-1941 (Box-folder 18:15)
    - High School Correspondence 1941-1942 (Box-folder 18:16)
    - High School Correspondence 1943 (Box-folder 18:17)
    - High School Correspondence 1944-1945 (Box-folder 18:18)
    - High School Minutes n.d. (Box-folder 19:1)
    - High School Minutes n.d. (Box-folder 19:2)
    - Minutes-Campus High School 1944-1946 (Box-folder 19:3)
    - High School Records 1941-1947 (Box-folder 19:4)
    - High School Enrollment/Rules n.d. (Box-folder 19:5)
    - High School Secondary School Conference 1942 (Box-folder 19:6)
    - High School Papers/Reports n.d. (Box-folder 19:7)
    - High School Petition n.d. (Box-folder 19:8)
    - Correspondence High School Counselor 1942-1945 (Box-folder 19:9)
    - Correspondence High school Counselor 1949-1951 (Box-folder 19:10)
    - Correspondence High School Counselor 1947-1948 (Box-folder 19:11)
    - High School Counselor Reports n.d. (Box-folder 19:12)
    - High School Records 1935-1940 (Box-folder 19:13)
    - High School Newsletter 1940 (Box-folder 19:14)
    - High School Records Schedule n.d. (Box-folder 19:15)
    - High School Records-Printed n.d. (Box-folder 19:16)
    - Home Economics Newsletter 1936 (Box-folder 19:17)
    - Inter-racial-Printed n.d. (Box-folder 19:18)
    - Inter-racial Correspondence 1942-1943 (Box-folder 19:19)
    - Inter-racial Minutes October 15, 1943 (Box-folder 19:20)
    - Interracial Work 1934-1937 (Box-folder 20:1)
    - Interracial Work Correspondence 1925-1933 (Box-folder 20:2)
    - Interracial Work Correspondence 1938-1940 (Box-folder 20:3)
    - Interracial Work Correspondence 1941-1950 (Box-folder 20:4)
    - Interracial Work Study Reports 1937 (Box-folder 20:5)
    - Interracial Work Reports 1931, 1950 (Box-folder 20:6)
    - Interracial Work Minutes 1931, 1945 (Box-folder 20:7)
    - Interracial Work Newsheet 1944 (Box-folder 20:8)
    - Interracial Work Related Groups n.d. (Box-folder 20:9)
    - Interracial Work Reading List n.d. (Box-folder 20:10)
    - Interracial Work Correspondence n.d. (Box-folder 20:11)
    - Interracial Work Correspondence n.d. (Box-folder 20:12)
    - Interracial Work Programs 1931-1933 (Box-folder 20:13)
    - jeanes Conference 1945 (Box-folder 20:14)
    - Jeanes Supervisory Conference 1935-1950 (Box-folder 20:15)
    - Jeanes Supervisor 1941-1950 (Box-folder 20:16)
    - Kappa Phi Kappa 1950-1953 (Box-folder 20:17)
    - Legislative Counsel 1926-1937 (Box-folder 20:18)
    - Library 1929-1951 (Box-folder 20:19)
    - Johnston Memorial Library Special Reports 1951 (Box-folder 20:20)
    - Matoaca Lab 1937-1944 (Box-folder 21:1)
    - Macklin 1940-41 (Box-folder 21:2)
    - Macklin 1942 (Box-folder 21:3)
    - Macklin 1943 (Box-folder 21:4)
    - Macklin 1944-1945 (Box-folder 21:5)
    - Macklin 1946 (Box-folder 21:6)
    - Music Festival Correspondence 1930-1933 (Box-folder 21:7)
    - Music Festival Correspondence 1934-1936 (Box-folder 21:8)
    - Music Department 1933, 1946-50 (Box-folder 21:9)
    - Music Department 1951 (Box-folder 21:10)
    - Music Department 1952 (Box-folder 21:11)
    - Music Festival Programs 1930-1932 (Box-folder 21:12)
    - Music Programs Printed (VSU) n.d. (Box-folder 21:13)
    - Music-Festval Correspondence n.d. (Box-folder 21:14)
    - National Assocition of College Women 1932-1952 (Box-folder 21:15)
    - National Association of College Women (Printed) n.d. (Box-folder 22:1)
    - National Education Association 1949-53 (Box-folder 22:2)
    - NEA Teachers Education 1945-1950 (Box-folder 22:3)
    - NEA Teachers Education 1945-1950 (Box-folder 22:4)
    - Negroes n.d. (Box-folder 22:5)
    - N.O.S. of Virginia Printed n.d. (Box-folder 22:6)
    - Negro Organization of Virginia Correspondence 1938-1953 (Box-folder 22:7)
    - Norfolk Division 1944 (Box-folder 22:8)
    - NYU Apprentice Teaching 1951-1952 (Box-folder 22:9)
    - NYU Apprentice Teaching 1951-1952 (Box-folder 22:10)
    - Philosophy of Education 1946-1947 (Box-folder 22:11)
    - Physical Education Dept 1948-1951 (Box-folder 22:12)
    - Physical Education Dept 1952 (Box-folder 22:13)
    - Printed Materials n.d. (Box-folder 22:14)
    - proposal- Summer Schoool for Negroes 1933 (Box-folder 22:15)
    - Proposal-Summer School for Negroes Improvememnts n.d. (Box-folder 22:16)
    - Proceedings and Reports 1943 (Box-folder 22:17)
    - Proceedings and Reports 1944 (Box-folder 22:18)
    - Proposal Basic Education 1950 (Box-folder 22:19)
    - Reading Clinic 1946-1947 (Box-folder 23:1)
    - Recommend Curriculum & Textbooks changes 1938-1945 (Box-folder 23:2)
    - Report-Basic Education n.d. (Box-folder 23:3)
    - Report-College of Secondary Relationship 1942 (Box-folder 23:4)
    - Report-Committee on Policies 1949 (Box-folder 23:5)
    - Report-Division of Education 1938-1939 (Box-folder 23:6)
    - Report: Workshop in Education 1943 (Box-folder 23:7)
    - Report-Instructors Activity 1938-1939 (Box-folder 23:8)
    - Report-Principals, School for Negroes 1939 (Box-folder 23:9)
    - Preliminary Report: Remedial Instructor 1946 (Box-folder 23:10)
    - Report-Summer School for Negroes 1932 (Box-folder 23:11)
    - Report-Summer School Demonstration 1936 (Box-folder 23:12)
    - Report of the Work at the Rocky Mountain Workshop 1938-1941 (Box-folder 23:13)
    - Roanoke Conference 1952 (Box-folder 23:14)
    - Miss E. Robinson 1942-1945 (Box-folder 23:15)
    - School of Education Meetings 1948 (Box-folder 23:16)
    - Secondary Education 1948-1950 (Box-folder 23:17)
    - Secondary Education 1928-1947 (Box-folder 23:18)
    - Secondary Education 1951 (Box-folder 23:19)
    - Secondary Education 1952 (Box-folder 24:1)
    - Secondary Education Department Minutes n.d. (Box-folder 24:2)
    - State Board of Education 1940-1943 (Box-folder 24:3)
    - State Board of Education 1944-1949 (Box-folder 24:4)
    - State Board of Education 1950-1952 (Box-folder 24:5)
    - State Board of Education Minutes Programs n.d. (Box-folder 24:6)
    - State Board of Virginia 1931-1932 (Box-folder 24:7)
    - Report-Study of Alumni n.d. (Box-folder 24:8)
    - The Study of Students n.d. (Box-folder 24:9)